おーす
Yo.
Ah, hello, Kodaka-sempai.
こんにちは　小鷹先輩
何だ　理科か
Oh, it's just Rika.
第一声からがっかりゼリフですか
That's the line you chose to open with?
それより理科　メガネどうしたんだ
Seriously, Rika, what happened to your glasses?
たまにはメガネなしもいいかなって
Rika thought it might be nice to go no-glasses.
イメチェンというやつですね
To try a new look, as they say.
コンタクトにしたのか
You switched to contacts?
理科はもともと伊達メガネだったんですよ
Oh, Rika's glasses were only
for show! Rika's vision is fine.
視力悪くないですし
何でまた伊達メガネなんか
Why would you wear glasses for show?
ファーションに決まってるんじゃないですか
For fashion's sake, of course!
I can't believe the word "fashion"
just came out of your mouth...
お前の口からファーションなんて言葉が
ならキャラ作りでは
"Character design," then?
Oh! Okay, that makes sense.
それなら納得だ
あっさり納得されると微妙に釈然としませんね
Rika's not sure she appreciates
how easily you accepted that...
で　どうですか先輩　今の理科
So, what do you think of the new Rika, Sempai?
例えるなら　野山に咲く一輪の花のような可憐さ
In descriptive terms, she's
pretty like a blooming wildflower...
好みか好みでないかといえば　正直
As for whether she's my type, I'd have to say...
ドストライクだ
Hell yeah.
い　いきなり何を言うんですか　先輩
Y-Y-You can't just burst out with that, Sempai!
あれ今　俺　口に出してだか
Wait, did I say that out loud?!
思い切り
Loud and clear!
What was that for?!
何すんだよ
別に
Nothing.
死ねばいいのに
I wish you'd drop dead.
兄貴
Aniki...
What's wrong with you guys?!
何だよ　お前ら
Kodaka-sempai!
小鷹先輩
BE MY FRIEND
Be My Friend
Shiranai furi shitatte
知らないフリしたって
Be My Side
BE MYSELF
Zenbu kizuiteta yo
全部気付いてるよ
Mou ippo kimi no tonari ni ikou
もう一歩
君の隣に行こう
Sono te ni datte todokisou sa
その手にだって届きそうさ
"Haganai NEXT"
想像しちゃダメ
Souzou ijou da ne jetto koosutaa na mainichi
ジェットコースターな毎日
Hisshi de mae wo muite itsumo kakenuketa n da
引き締めて前を向いて
いつも駆け抜けたら
Zutto tsuzuki wa shinai ne bokura no jikan wa
ずっと続きはしないね
僕らの時間は今しかないから
Ima shika nai kara kono shunkan kizamitsukeyou
この瞬間刻みづけよう
Be My Friend
BE MY FRIEND
Shiranai furi shitatte
知らないフリしたって
Be My Side
BE MYSELF
Zenbu kizuiteta yo
全部気付いてるよ
Mou ippo kimi no tonari ni ikou
もう一歩
君の隣に行こう
受け止めるように
Te wo toreru you ni
Be My Friend
BE MY FRIEND
Miagete bakari datte
見上げてばかりだって
Be My Side
BE MYSELF
Akogareteru ima mo
憧れてる今も
Mou ikkai nando demo te wo nobasou
もう一回
何度でも手を伸ばそう
Ano hoshi datte todokisou sa
あの星だって届きそうさ
"Homo Game Club"
I had no idea Kodaka-sempai felt
such a strong sexual attraction to Rika!
小鷹先輩が理科にそこまで性的な魅力を感じていたなんて
Okay, let's do the dirty! Right now!
さあ　嫌らしいことしましょう　今すぐに
Idiot!
アホか
Oops, Rika was a little too vulgar.
This is the time for classy language.
ちょっと品がなさすぎましたね
ここは上品な日本語で
Will you kindly do the dirty with me, Sempai?
理科とお嫌らしいことをしましょう　先輩
How was that "classy"?
どこが上品だ
Why do you have to be Rika, anyway?
何でお前が理科なんだろうな
Is it that painful to find Rika hot?
You're making Rika want to cry now.
ここまで悔しがることですか
こっちのほうが泣きたくなりますよ
Okay, guess I'll study now.
じゃ　勉強でもするか
He doesn't even try to patch up
the wound he gave Rika's heart!
理科の心に傷を負わせたフォローもなし
It's too brutal! But that actually
makes him more... Oh, how painful!
鬼畜過ぎます
でもそれが逆に　悔しい
But Rika's hot and bothered!
でも感じちゃう
Fine, never mind.
もういいです
Rika will escape into the 2D
world to soothe her bruised heart.
理科二次元に逃避して傷付いた心を慰めます
Sena-sempai? May Rika please borrow the TV?
星奈先輩
テレビお借りしていいですか
Sure. Going to play a game?
いいわよ　ゲームするの
I'm going to watch an anime.
アニメ見るんです
I got this from Amazoness yesterday.
It's the movie version of Homo Game Club...
昨日アマゾネスから届いた「ホモゲ部」の劇場版ですが…
Homo Game Club
How dare you suggest playing such
a disgraceful thing in our club room?
部室でなんて破廉恥なものを流そうとしてるんだ
It's not disgraceful at all!
破廉恥なんかじゃありません
True, it is based on a boys' love game
rated for adults ages 18 and up only,
確かにこのソフトは18禁BLゲームが原作になっていますが
but the TV anime cut all the explicit graphics,
テレビ版では過激な描写などは削られて
and it was reborn as a work
children of any age can safely enjoy!
小さなお子さんも安心して楽しめる作品に生まれ変わったのです
劇場版では若干セクシーな描写も増えましたが
The movie has somewhat
upped the number of sexy shots,
but the fact remains that it's
geared toward the general market!
一般向け作品であることに違いはありません
So what? Who cares about stuff like that?!
知るか　どうでもいいそんなこと
Rika cares! Here, look closely.
どうでもよくありません
ほら　よく見てください
Don't bring that thing near me.
近付けるな　そんなもの
"Homo Game Club The Movie"
"~This Is Our True Fortune~"
There's no 18+ rating on it, right?
18禁マークないでしょう
Whether it's 18+ or not, there's no way an anime
18禁であろうとなかろうと
そんな怪しげなタイトルで怪しげなパッケージのアニメがまともなはずがない
with that sketchy title and
sketchy packaging is anything decent!
Rika doesn't think it's good to judge a
book by its cover without even looking inside.
内容も見てないのに印象だけで判断するのはよくないと思います
I agree. You shouldn't
judge things by appearances.
確かに　見た目だけで判断するのはよくないと思う
Kodaka-sempai!
小鷹先輩
You should take a look at
what's inside before you reject them.
否定するにしても中身を見てからにすべきだ
It hurts to be rejected just
for how you look, you know.
外見だけで否定されるのはな
つらいもんだよ
I-If that's how you feel, Kodaka...
小鷹がそう言うなら
Leave it to you, Kodaka-sempai!
さすがです　小鷹先輩
Okay, you should watch Homo
Game Club with us, Yozora-sempai!
それじゃ夜空先輩も一緒に見ましょう「ホモゲ部」
"Homo Game Club The Movie"
"~This Is Our True Fortune~"
This movie is a reconstruction of
the TV series with new scenes added,
内容はテレビ版を再構築して　新作カットを加えたものなので
so I think you'll be okay
without any background!
一見さんでも大丈夫だと思いますから
Homo Game Club The Movie
~This Is Our True Fortune~
Boys' Bathroom
"Ecstasy"
Want to give it a go?
やらないか
I-I'm not interested in homoge!
[homoge: pornographic game
featuring sex between men]
俺はホモゲーなんて興味ねえよ
A fan-made game, huh? Sounds interesting.
同人ゲームか　面白そうだな
Will you do it for me, Fumio?
やってくれるか　史雄
Leave it to me, Koyomi!
任せてくれ　暦
I can't believe it... Not even
one person bought our game!
まさか　俺達のゲームが一本も売れないなんて
Homoge
You idiot!
馬鹿野郎
You know there's something
more important than sales!
売り上げなんかより大事なものがあるだろう
I'll do away with the
Homo Game Club once and for all!
ホモゲ部など　この私が滅ぼしてやる
"Very Dangerous!!"
I'll never let you do that!
そんなことは絶対にさせない
You're blocking the screen.
見づれえよ
I swear I'll protect you, even if
I have to go against the whole world.
俺はたとえ　世界の全てを敵に回そうとも
お前を絶対に守ってみせる
That's my line.
それは俺のセリフだ
Let's fight together for what's important to us!
大切なもののため　共に戦おう
What do you think, Yozora-sempai?
どうですか　夜空先輩
I-It's okay, I guess.
まあまあだな
そうか　そんなことがあったのか
I see, so that's what happened to you...
Thank you for sharing that with me, Koyomi.
話してくれてありがとう　暦
Fumio...
史雄
Huh?
Huh?!
The End
Two hours simply flew by.
あっという間の二時間でした
Thank you for showing us this great movie.
よいものを見せていただきました
理科
Rika...
Yes?
はい
Why did Fumio and Koyomi, um... k-kiss?
何で史雄と暦はその
キ　キスをしたのだ
何でって
"Why"? Of course people kiss
when their emotions are running high!
お互いの気持ちが盛り上がったらそりゃあキスしますよ
B-But, those two are friends... friends do that?
だ　だが　あの二人は友達　なのに
するのか
Yes, they do. It's the human impulse.
しますね　それが人間と言うものです
Still, for friends to do one so...
steamy... Isn't that weird?
だからって　友達同士であんな　濃厚なのを
変だろう
Not one bit!
ちっとも変じゃありません
When two people's hearts are strongly connected,
心が強く結ばれた二人が次にお互いの体を求め合うのは当然のことです
to desire a joining of the
flesh is the natural next step!
友達同士だろうが　男同士だろうが
Though they may be friends,
though they may be two men,
they lock lips and spread
legs with the one they love!
好きな人とはチューしてエッチするんです
It is a law of nature!
それが自然の摂理なんです
Don't say "though they
may be two men" so lightly.
さらりと男同士だろうがとか言うんじゃねえよ
I see... So even friends kiss each other.
そうか　友達同士でもキスするんだ
H-Hmph!
I admit, I shouldn't have judged by appearances.
確かに偏見でものを言ったのは悪かった
And Rika may take that to mean
you've awakened as a fellow yaoi fangirl?!
ということは　夜空先輩も腐の道に目覚めてくれたんですね
N-No, I haven't!
べ　別にそういうわけではない
I'm just saying Homo Game Club
was pretty good. That's all.
ただ「ホモゲ部」はなかなかよかった
それだけだ
喜んでいただけて嬉しいです
Rika is so glad you enjoyed it!
If there are any other good ones, bring them in.
ほかにも何かいい作品があったら持ってくるがいい
Yes!
はい
つい念願のお仲間が
At last, Rika's longed-for comrade!
Yet if Rika makes a wrong
choice now, it will come to nothing.
しかしここでチョイスを誤っては水の泡です
落ち着くのです　志熊理科
Be calm, Shiguma Rika!
My Baby Maker Can't Be This Cute
is a macho-homo masterpiece,
「俺のイチ●●こんなに可愛いわけがない」は雅致な傑作なんですが
but there are only
18+ versions, which is an obstacle.
18禁版しか出ていないのがネック
And Nyaro-san: Another Nestling Chaos
would dive straight into tentacle fare...
「擦り寄れ！　ネアルさん」もいきなりの触手系だと
Hey, hey, Yozora!
ちょっと　ちょっと　夜空
何だ　肉
What, Meat?
何だじゃないわよ
You know "what"! You always badmouth
my gal games and call them creepy,
あたしのギャルゲーはキモイとか
散々扱き下ろしたくせに
so how come Rika's gay anime is okay?!
なんで理科のホモアニメはオーケーなのよ
"Homo Game Club"
ふん　隣人部の活動目的に相応しい
Don't compare this work depicting
noble friendship between two boys,
a theme appropriate to the
goals of the Neighbors Club,
男同士の崇高な友情を描いた作品と
to games where you do lewd
things with other girls, stupid Meat!
女共といかがわしいことをするゲームを一緒にするな　馬鹿肉目
I won't let you get away
with making fun of gal games!
ギャルゲーを馬鹿にしたら許さないわよ
Try reading the scene you're
doing in this game out loud, then.
だったら今貴様がやっているこのシーンを声に出して読んでみろ
From your face, it must
be another one so disgraceful
その様子だと　また口にするのも憚れるような破廉恥な内容のようだな
you can't even bear to say it.
こっ　このシーンは　ちょうどたまたまアレなシーンだから
Th-This particular scene just
happens to be one of those...
Just so you know, I could read any
scene from Homo Game Club out loud.
ちなみに私は「ホモゲ部」のいかなるシーンも読み上げることができるぞ
Because Homo Game Club is a noble work!
「ホモゲ部」は崇高な作品だからな
All right, try it, then!
だったらやってみなさいよ
Oh, this scene. I remember it.
この場面か　覚えている
I swear I'll protect you, even if
I have to go against the whole world.
俺はたとえ　世界の全てを敵に回そうとも
お前を絶対に守ってみせる
That's my line.
それは俺のセリフだ
Let's fight together for what's important to us!
大切なもののため　共に戦おう
Why did it happen to
land on cool-sounding lines?!
何でタイミングよく格好いいセリフが出てくんだよ
We're doing a different scene.
だったら別の場面よ
No matter what stands in my way,
たとえ目の前にどんな障害が立ちはだかろうとも
俺の進む道を止めることなど出来ない
it can never stop me from walking my path!
Gah, that's it! Why are there so
many gratuitously cool lines?! Idiot!
ああもう　なんで無駄に格好いいセリフがいっぱいあるのよ馬鹿
Because it's all the most
famous scenes from the TV show!
テレビの名場面を凝縮してありますからね
If you can't say you like what you like,
好きなものを好きだと言えないのなら
それは世界のほうが間違っているのではないだろうか
don't you think it might be the
world, and not you, that's wrong?
Noooo! Another cool one!
また格好いいし
Big talk for some sloppy muscleman!
むさい筋肉だるまのくせに
Don't underestimate Misao.
美佐男をなめるなよ
よく一字一句を覚えてるもんだ
I'm amazed she remembers every word...
さて　私はこれくらいでいいだろう　肉
Now, I believe I've done enough.
Meat.
そろそろ貴様にもやってもらおうか
How about you take a turn now?
What's wrong, Meat?
どうした　肉
If there's nothing to be
ashamed of in your game,
貴様がやっているゲームに何一つ恥じることないのなら
read the dialogue in this
scene to us loud and clear!
このシーンのセリフを大声で読み上げるがいい
Go on.
さあ
Go on!
Gah!
わかったわよ　やってやろじゃない
Fine! I will, then!
It's like what they just said in that anime, anyway!
今まさにそのアニメでも言ってたしね
If you can't say you like what
you like, it's the world that's wrong!
好きなものを好きと言えないのなら　世界のほうが間違ってるって
To defend the honor of "One Day I Suddenly
Got a Blond Little Sister with Pigtails
あたしもこの
「ある日突然金髪ツインテールの妹が出来ちゃって
and I Can't Take It Anymore,"
僕もう我慢できない」
の名誉を守るために
I, too, shall battle the world!
世界と戦うわ
What's with that title?
何　そのタイトル
I-I'm reading...
読むわよ
"B-Big Brother, thrust
your big, th-thick th... th..."
お兄ちゃんの　熱くて　大き…　お　お
What?
お兄ちゃんの　熱くて　大き…
"Big Brother, thrust your...
b-b-big, thick th..."
Read it louder, and clearer, and with feeling!
もっと大きな声ではっきりと感情を込めて
Big Brother, thrust your big, thick [bleep] deep in
my [bleep] and [bleep] your [bleep] milk inside me!
お兄ちゃんの熱くて大き…
Sh-She actually said it...
言いおった
I won't let you always win, you know.
何時までもやられっぱなしのあたしじゃないのよ
I didn't think the line would be so...that...
まさかそこまでアレなセリフだったとは
Well? I said it.
どう　言ってやったわよ
Now do you understand that this
game is in no way embarrassing?
これで　このゲームが全然恥ずかしいものなんかじゃないってわかった
あ　ああ　うん　私の負けでいいです
Ah, y-yes. We'll say I lost this round.
L-Look in my direction and say that!
ちょっ　ちゃんとこっち見て言ってよ
Even Rika might not be able to say that one.
さすがに今のは理科でもちょっと口に出せないですね
I am humbly impressed. I did
not know you were such a deviant.
恐れ入りました　星奈の姉御は痴女だったのですね
Well, um, I definitely understand
that you treasure that game.
まあ　そのう　なんだ
お前がそのゲームを大切に思う気持ちがよくわかった
I'm sorry for making fun of it.
馬鹿にして　すまなかった
Yozora, you're a perverted homoge maniac!
夜空の変態ホモゲーマニア
Final exams are over at last.
やっと終わった　期末テスト
Hey, you troubled lamb over there!
ちょっとそこの悩める子羊…君
Come on, don't ignore me, Lamb!
こらこら　無視するんじゃないよ　子羊君
Turning your back on a servant of God like me
神に仕える私に背を向けるってことは
means you're a sinner
who's turned away from God!
神に背きし咎人だよ
Er, I guess there's no chance you don't mean me?
えーと　もしかしなくても俺ですか
Natch! Or "naturally," I should say!
うん　もろちん　じゃなくてもちろんね
Oopsy-daisy...
どっこいしょ
"Oopsy-daisy"?
どっこいしょって　何か用ですか
Do you need something?
Just figured I'd say, "If you've
got any troubles, I'm here to listen."
なんちゅうか　悩みがあるなら聞くよって
Since I'm a Sister.
自分シスターなんで
Well, I'm not completely trouble-free...
そりゃまあ　なくはないですけど
I hear you! A lot can happen in life, right?
わかるよ　人生いろいろあるよね
I can get why you'd go astray like that!
だからそんなふうにぐれちゃうのも無理はないよね
あのう　髪の毛のことならこれは地毛ですけど
Er, if you're talking
about my hair, it's natural.
What? That's natural?!
地毛なん
そっか　地毛か
Huh, so that's natural...
まあ　人生いろいろあるよね
Well, a lot can happen in life!
She just glossed it over!
誤魔化した
Sorry for stopping you.
Anyway, if you do have any troubles,
呼び止めて悪かったね
まあ　悩みがあったら生徒相談室に来んさいな
come over to the student counseling center.
私は高山ケイト
I'm Takayama Kate.
Some kids call me "Kate-chan" or "Mother Kate."
ケイトちゃんとか　マザーケイトって呼ぶ子もいるね
高山
Takayama?
Big Brother!
お兄ちゃん
お兄ちゃんがおるげ
Hey, it's Big Brother!
I found Big Brother!
お兄ちゃんがおった
Oh, Maria, is this person?
そうだ　マリア　この人
Wh-Wh-What are you doing
here with Big Brother, you hag?!
何で　婆がお兄ちゃんといるんだ
So you do know her.
やっぱり知り合いだったのか
Ma-ri-a...
誰が婆じゃ　誰が
- Who do you think you're calling a hag?!
- That hurts, stop it! Die, poopy crappy hag!
やめろ　うんこ婆死ね
I'm not "hag," I'm "Big Sister," now aren't I?
婆じゃなくて　お姉様だろう
Shut up, poopy crappy hag!
うるせぇ　うんこ糞婆
うんこと糞がだぶってるぞ　うんこ糞マリア
"Poopy crappy" is redundant, poopy crappy Maria!
Ow!
痛い　死ね死ねうんこ婆　うんこ
Die! Die, poopy hag! Poop...
Come on, say it. "Big Sister."
ほれ　言って見そ
お　姉　様
It hurts, it hurts! I'm sorry!
I was wrong, Big Sis...hag.
痛い痛い　御免なさい　私が悪かったです　お姉さ…婆
Still saying that, you filthy brat?!
まだ言うか　このガキ畜生
Please forgive me, Big Sister!
許してください　お姉様
So, are you Hasegawa Kodaka?
ところで君は羽瀬川小鷹君かい
Y-Yes.
はい
I see. My little sister
talks about you all the time.
そうか　妹のマリアからいつも聞いてるよ
Little sister?
妹
うん　私はマリアのお姉様だよ
Yep. I'm Maria's big sister.
But now I get it. So you're
the famous Big Brother Kodaka.
しかしなるほどね
君が噂の小鷹お兄ちゃんだったのかい
She's a moron, obviously, but take
good care of her, okay Kodaka-kun?
見てのとおり馬鹿な妹だけど
宜しく頼むよ　小鷹君
Hmph!
ふーんだ
Big Brother is Big Brother whether
a hag asks him to be or not! You crap!
婆なんかに頼まれなくて
お兄ちゃんはお兄ちゃんなのだ　糞が
Make sure you do your work!
ちゃんと仕事しろよ
Don't wanna!
やなこっだ
That kid...
Sheesh, why'd she turn out
so dumb, anyway? You know?
ったく　どうしてあんな馬鹿な妹になっちまったんだろうね
ねえ
Still, I am grateful to you... all of you.
でもまあ　君には
君達には感謝してるんだよね
"All of you"?
君達
It's the "Neighbors Club," right?
隣人部だっけ
Maria's been in better spirits
since she became your advisor.
その顧問になってからマリアは元気になったよ
Really? It seemed to me like
she was always high-spirited.
そうですか　あいつはもともと元気だったような
Actually, no.
そうでもないよ
That idiot's never been able to
do anything but get good grades,
あの馬鹿　昔からお勉強しか出来ない馬鹿だったから
so she gets conceited and
looks down on other people.
思い上がって　周りを見下すんだよね
And she's only gotten vainer
since she skipped all those grades...
飛び級で上に行ってからにはますます増長してさ
So having you and your little sister...
can I call her "Poopy Vampire"?
だからまあ　小鷹君や君の妹の
うんこ吸血鬼ちゃんっていいのかね
あと　三日月夜空さん　彼女には特に感謝してるんだ
And Mikazuki Yozora.
I'm especially grateful to her.
To Yozora?
夜空に
We never knew how to interact
with Maria, so we were at a loss.
私達はマリアにどう接していいのかわからず戸惑ってた
But Mikazuki-san ignored her protests
and dragged her out into the world.
三日月さんはそんなマリアを問答無用で外に連れ出してくれたんだ
That's what Maria needed most then.
あの時のマリアにはあれが一番必要だった
マリアにとって彼女は
I guess she was the first stranger Maria met
勉強ができるってカードがまったく効かない
that she couldn't play the "I'm smart" card on.
初めての他人だったのさ
Oh...
Gratitude to Yozora... I didn't see that coming.
まさか夜空が感謝されるなんてな
I'm not a fan of letting kids
run around naked, though.
でも子供を全裸で走らせるのはちょっとどうかなっと思うけどね
I-I'm sorry! I'll talk to her.
すっ　すいません　注意します
Anyway, keep up the good
work with her... Big Brother.
まあ　とにかく　これからもよろしく頼むよ　お兄ちゃん
Yes, Ma'am... wait, "Big Brother"?
はい　ってお兄ちゃん
マリアのお兄ちゃんなら　私にとってもお兄ちゃんっしょ
If you're Maria's big brother,
then you're mine too, aren't you?
I mean, I'm fifteen.
私は15才だし
Okay, bye-bye, Big Brother!
じゃ　バイバイ　お兄ちゃん
Whoops, I farted.
おっと　屁が出た
小鷹
Kodaka.
I thought you'd be in the club room by now.
先に部室に行ってるかと思ったぞ
No, I ran into somebody kinda strange...
いや　ちょっと変なやつに会ってさ
Somebody strange?
変なやつ
By the way, Kodaka...
時に小鷹
Finals are over now...
期末テストも終わったわけだが
Yeah.
Rumor has it that people with friends
噂によると友達がいる人間は
do something called
"comparing their answers" after tests.
テストが終わったら答え合わせというものをするらしいぞ
Oh, yeah, I hear some regions have that custom.
一部の地方にはそんな風習もあるみたいだな
そ　そうだな　まったくくだらん風習だ
Y-Yes, it's a totally
pointless custom, isn't it?
But Kodaka, in the future when we make friends,
しかし　小鷹
将来友達が出来た時
we might be forced to do the
"compare answers" thing between classes.
休み時間に答え合わせを付き合わされることがあるかもしれない
そうかもな
True.
So... w-we're going to prepare for
that by practicing comparing test answers!
だから　そ　その時に備えて練習するぞ
テストの答え合わせの
O-Okay, got it.
おー　わかった
Right... We'll compare answers on
Math II, Section 3, Question 4, then.
では数学2の四角3の問い4の答え合わせが
Math II? But that was on the first day!
数2って　初日の科目じゃねえか
I don't remember the questions or my answers.
覚えてねえよ　問題も自分の答えも
That's what I'm most worried about.
私が一番不安なのはそれなのだ
What kind of question was it?
どんな問題
配点15点の証明問題で
It was a proof worth 15 points.
Oh, that one! Mine got really long,
but I'm not too confident about it...
ああ　あれか
すげえ長くなったけど自信ないな
つうか　証明問題の答え合わせを立ち話でやるのはきつくないか
But isn't it kind of rough trying to
compare proofs standing outside?
You've got a point...
それもそうか
Maybe the right move is to say
"That one was hard" or "I think I got it"
確かにこれは「難しかったねえ」とか
「私は自信があるぞ」と言った話の種にするのが妥当なのかもしれない
to just get the conversation flowing.
Okay.
よし
That question was hard, huh!
あの問題難しかったね
Yes, it was!
そうだね
Let's use a different question!
ほかの問題の答え合わせをしよう
Let's make it a multiple-choice
or fill-in-the-blank one!
選択問題とか穴埋め問題にしようぜ
Preferably one we did today.
できれば今日やったやつで
今日で不安なのは
One from today that worries me...
Problem 11 from Section 2 of Japanese History.
日本史の四角2の11だな
Hold on a sec.
ちょっと待ってくれ
Let's see...
えっと
"After Hojo Tokimune's death,
powerful vassal Adachi Yasumori
北条時宗の死後
有力御家人の安達泰盛が内管領（11）に滅ぼされた
was overthrown by Inner
Administrator blank number eleven."
Definitely Taira Yoritsuna, I'm sure of it.
これは平頼綱だな　自信ある
Well, of course I know that.
あ　いや　それはもちろんわかるんだ
だが　もしかすると
But I think I might have
written the "tsuna" part
平頼綱の「綱」という漢字を　「網」と間違えて書いたかもしれない
with the kanji for "net" instead of "rope."
What am I supposed to do about it?!
知らねえよ　そんなの
I'm really worried... Which one
is "net," and which one is "rope"?
大丈夫かな　本当に
どっちか「綱」で　どっちが「網」だったか
They are similar, but...
確かに似てるけど
Taira Yoritsuna
Wait...
Are you sure you didn't misspell it
when you wrote the answer, Kodaka?
小鷹も解答欄に「平頼網」と書いているのではないか
Crap, now you've got me worried too!
やべえよ　俺まで不安になってきたじゃねえか
I wrote it right, didn't I?
ちゃんと「綱」で書いたよな
I'm not so sure.
それはどうかな
Now I'm worried about the
parts I used to be confident about?!
自信のあったとこまで不安になるとは
This "comparing answers" thing is fearsome!
答え合わせ恐るべしだ
It really is.
そうだな
Okay, then, next one. Number 18 in Section 2.
さて　それじゃ次の問題だ
四角2の18
Hmm... "In Year 1 of the Shochu Era,
blank number eighteen, Emperor Go-Daigo"...
正中元年（18）に後醍醐天皇が
I just guessed on this...
これ適当に埋めた
Year 1324!
1324年
Oh, it's Sena.
なんだ　星奈か
Whatcha doing? That "comparing answers" thing?
何々　答え合わせってやつ
Yep.
Then I'll be nice and join you!
それなら　あたしもやってあげるわ
You're pretty lucky, getting
to hear my perfect answers!
あたしの完璧な回答で答え合わせができるなんて運がよかったわね
We don't need you. Scram.
貴様などいらん　消えろ
What's the problem? Let me do it too!
いいじゃない　あたしにも答え合わせさせてよ
Math II, Section 3, Question 5, then.
じゃあ　数学2の四角3の5
Hmm... 4 times the square root of 5!
えっと　4ルート5
何でこいつら問題番号だけでわかるんだ
How do they know the questions by number?
Classical Japanese,
Section 2, Question 1 part 3!
古文の四角2の問い1の3
さ行変化活用
Sa-line irregular conjugation!
What? Consonant-stem conjugation?
五段活用
You got that one wrong, huh Yozora?
間違えたんだ　なあ夜空
Come on, come on, what's the next question?
ほらほら次の問題は
We're done. Comparing answers
really is a waste of time, isn't it?
もういい　やはり答え合わせなど時間の無駄だな
It's not like it changes your test scores.
それでテストの点数が変わるわけでもないし
負け惜しみ
Sour grapes?
Wait, Yozora!
ちょっと　夜空
Give me a question! A question!
問題出してよ　問題
I don't care how hard it is!
どんだけ難しいやつでもいいから
No. Comparing answers with you is no fun.
いい　貴様と答え合わせをしても楽しくない
じゃあ　中二の時の隣の席の山本さんと同じこと言わないでよ
But... Don't say that, it's what Yamamoto
who sat next to me in eighth grade said!
貴様と答え合わせをするくらいなら
I'd rather compare answers
with Tomo-chan than you.
私は朋ちゃんとする
Say, Tomo-chan, what did you put for
Question 7 in Section 2 of the bio exam?
なあ　朋ちゃん
生物の四角2の7は何で書いた
Hey! Don't mumble crazy
things to yourself, ask me...
ちょっと　わけわかんない独り言言ってないで　あたしと
Oh! The answer to that
one is "Calvin-Benson cycle"!
あっ　それの答えは　カルビン・ベンソン回路
I wasn't sure, but I put "Calvin-Benson cycle."
私はとりあえず　カルビン・ベンソン回路と書いておいた
Oh, that's what you put too,
Tomo-chan? I feel better, then!
朋ちゃんもそう書いたか　これで一安心だな
Hey! Listen to me, Yozora!
ちょっと聞いてよ　夜空
Hikatta hazu no ano hoshi
光ったはずの星
Mayotta kumo ga jama shite mienaku naru
迷った雲が邪魔して
見えなくなる
Nani wo shinjitara ii?
何を信じたらいい
Fuantei sugiru sekai de
不安定すぎる世界で
Sodatta takaramono kowashikaketeta
育った宝物壊しかけてた
Nakusu no ga kowakute
なくすのが怖くて
Fujouri datte tameiki tsuki
不条理だって
ため息つき
どうにかどうで足掻いてた日々
Torikago de agaiteta hibi
Onaji sora wo miageteta n da bokura wa
同じ空を見上げてたんだ
僕らは
Kimi no te wo nigitta
toki nigirikaeshite kureta ne
君の手を握った時
握り返してくれたね
Tsunagatta kono te wa
donna hane yori tsuyoi n da
繋がったこの手は
どんな羽より強いんだ
Tsubasa nante nakutatte motto takaku toberu kara
翼だってなくったって
もっと高く飛べるから
Kitto ima nara daijoubu
きっと今なら大丈夫
Oozora kagayaku hoshi wo tsukamou
大空輝く星を掴もう
やっと試験が終わったな
Phew, exams are finally over!
地道に勉強してたからなんとかなったけど難しかったぜ
I was dedicated about studying,
so I got through them, but it was rough.
ちなみに夏休みの後に期末試験があるのは
By the way, the reason we
had finals after summer vacation
うちの学校が二学期制だからだ
is because our school is on the two-term system.
誰に説明してるんだ
ともかく　試験も終わったことだし
Who's that explanation for?
Anyway, now that exams are over...
次の試験に向けて勉強しないとな
Yeah, now we have to study for the next tests!
真面目か
次回　「俺の妹達がこんなに可愛い」
Seriously?!
"My Little Sisters Are
This Cute"
Next time: "My Little Sisters Are This Cute."
小鷹　やっぱりシスコンだったのか
So you really have a sister complex, Kodaka?